♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Red] How do we get Ibyang from Atoy?
[Martina] We need to find someone
who can pretend
to be Ibyang's real mother.
What? An actress?
[Martina, in English] Something like that.
Mom, wake up, Mom!
[in English] I'm Olga Bonifacio.
Olga, for short.
Pretend you gave up
your child for adoption.
[Red] Then after a long time,
you meet again and want to reunite.
[sobs] My child…
It's me.
It's me, your mama.
I want to make it up to you
if you'll let me.
- [in English] Cut.
- [Charmi] Um, Ms. Ame?
Where can we meet Ibyang?
So we can bring her mother to you.
What's her name?
[Charmi] Olga Bonifacio.
You know, this place looks familiar to me.
[vocal exercising]
- [Atoy] Olga?
- [Ame] Atoy!
[Ame] She's Ibyang's mother!
[Atoy] Her?
How did you meet?
- [Atoy] Oh.
- [Olga] Oh, what's that? Oh!
- [Olga] What--
- [Atoy] Oh, sorry-- Oh!
- [in English] Sorry. Sorry.
- What's that?
PREVIOUSLY
[Olga] What's your name?
Uh, Atoy.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Aren't you moving a bit too fast, miss?
Don't you want us
- to get to know each other first?
- What else do you want to know?
[music swells]
♪ Fix this ♪
[music fades]
- She approached me.
- Destiny.
- What?
- [quirky sting]
- Well, we bumped into each other
- [sneaky music playing]
while I was looking for the church
of San Antonio de Padua.
I thought he was the answer to my prayers,
but… nothing.
- He ghosted me.
- Huh?
How could I call you?
The number got erased from my palm.
Why did you write it on my palm?
Of course it would get erased!
- Oh.
- Excuses, my God.
You should've remembered it.
Okay? Or… at least looked for me.
Right? Around.
You know, if you want something,
you'll find a way,
and that's what
I'm doing now to see my child.
Ah.
[sneaky music playing]
Where is she?
[scoffs]
- Is this her room?
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What now?
How can I be sure
you're really Ibyang's mother?
As far as I know…
[suspicious music playing]
…her parent's name is Martin.
[Martina, in English]
You need to watch out for Atoy.
He's Ibyang's guardian,
and he's not very easily convinced.
Atoy. That name sounds familiar.
Don't worry, madam.
My friend's charm is something else.
That Atoy, he'll fold. Right?
He should.
[in English] I mean,
you're getting paid well enough.
‪[inaudible]
- [Red] Oh.
- Oh.
This is the complete amount
- for the first month.
- [in English] Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Remember, do your job well.
That's big money.
So, there's no backing out,
and do everything we tell you properly,
because if not,
I'll bury you alive.
[music fades]
Really? Oh.
Ah-- Just kidding.
- [Olga chuckles]
- My comedy is dark.
[both chuckling]
[sinister music playing]
As long as the money keeps coming,
consider it done.
[music fades]
[in English] Excuse me?
[sighs]
Just because you saw
"Martin" written down,
doesn't mean I'm fake, okay?
‪[scoffs]
Martin is my ex.
He's Ibyang's real father.
[suspicious music playing]
What?
Are you sure?
Well, if you don't believe me,
do a DNA test.
But you'll pay, okay?
- It's expensive. It's really expensive.
- [Charmi] Right?
Oh, Atoy, Sister Norma
already gave her blessing.
Even her niece is here.
[Olga] Atoy.
I know I made a big mistake
leaving Ibyang with Sister Norma.
[melancholic music playing]
But what could I do?
I had no money, no job.
I know I was a bad mother.
But now, I want to make up for it.
That's why I'm working hard
to have my own house,
to start a business.
I'm even taking side jobs,
so I can have a career as an actress.
Oh, you know, that's possible.
You're beautiful. Ibyang takes after you.
Not a day passed
that I didn't think of her.
I searched for her for so long.
So, I hope
you'll let me see the child.
[music turns dramatic]
[music fades]
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
[snipping]
[sewing machine clacking]
[gun cocks]
[gunshots]
[snipping]
[electronic blipping]
[music fades]
‪[footsteps approaching]
Oh, drink some water first.
- Oh, thank you.
- She's coming down.
[Atoy] Ibyang.
[melodramatic music playing]
She's Olga.
She's your mother.
My child…
- [sentimental music playing]
- [gasping]
[music fades]
There.
[in English] Prettiness.
[soft chuckle]
[somber music playing]
Are you really my mama?
[melancholic music playing]
Yes, child.
Why did you leave me?
Because your mother was foolish. [inhales]
I was afraid
I couldn't give you a good life.
I knew you'd suffer more
if you were with me.
But I'm suffering too.
[music fades]
Good thing
kind people took care of me.
Did you give me away because…
- you didn't love me?
- Oh my. No, no.
It wasn't like that, child. My child…
It wasn't like that.
I love you.
When you love someone…
[sobs] you don't give them away.
[sobbing]
[Olga] Forgive me, my child.
Mommy made a mistake.
But I'm here now.
We'll be together.
[sobs] And if you'll agree…
we'll go home.
[melodramatic music playing]
If you're going to take me…
can it be the day after tomorrow instead?
I want to spend time
with Sis Ame and Tatoy.
Okay.
[music swells]
[music turns dramatic]
- Oh my.
- [Charmi] Oh?
What happened?
Why aren't you with the child?
She said she still wants to spend time
with Ame and Atoy for a while.
You know, I'm nervous, like…
I can't relax.
Oh. Why?
Because of Atoy.
He's so suspicious of me!
He even introduced me
to Ibyang as her mother, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- But I could see it on his face,
he's full of doubt!
Oh, God. What more does he want?
Didn't you say
you're willing to do a DNA test?
But he didn't entertain that idea.
Oh, why?
I'm willing to give a DNA test.
Madam even prepared samples here, see,
in case they ask me for a DNA test.
[Charmi] And this?
Is this from Ibyang's real mother?
I don't know.
Maybe.
[suspicious music playing]
[music swells]
[music fades]
Oh. Hey, the water!
- Hey! What water?
- The water! Oh, no!
- Did you leave boiling water at home?
- Oh, no. Not that!
The-- The water bottle
I was holding earlier… It's gone.
[sighs] Maybe Atoy took it,
because he plans to have me
DNA tested without me knowing.
Sis, what now? You'll be exposed as fake!
No. We-- We need to find a way
around this.
- Really, sis!
- Ah, we can't leave.
Wait, um…
Wait. I'll ask Madam for help.
[tense music playing]
[line ringing]
Hello, madam?
Madam, there's…
there's just a slight problem.
Please don't be angry.
Um, bu-- but… I already thought of a way.
Yes, I already-- It's okay now.
[in English] What? What do you mean?
[suspicious music playing]
[in English] Okay.
I'll try to get what you need.
Huh?
Why that brand of bottled water?
[in English] Okay.
Just don't get caught.
[music fades]
Ma'am, moscato.
Uh, where's Audrey?
Outside, ma'am. Doing yoga.
[in English] Okay.
[in English] I think maybe you should
bring her some snacks.
Also, do we still have
that Pure Dia water?
I'll check the pantry, ma'am,
if we have it.
- Okay. Give that if ever, okay?
- Okay.
[in English] Thank you.
[suspicious music playing]
[music fades]
Audrey.
[in English] Uh,
Janine is looking for you.
[mysterious music playing]
[Audrey] Janine!
[tense music playing]
[line ringing]
[in English] Hello? Yes, Olga.
I have what you need.
Where will my staff meet you?
[music swells]
[in English] All right. Good.
‪[dramatic sting]
Is it true?
Ibyang's mother showed up?
Mm.
Too bad! I didn't catch her!
I didn't see her!
Too bad.
Why do you look… unhappy?
Ah!
[giggles]
I know.
You don't want Ibyang
taken from you, right?
Oh, no! [chuckles]
'Toy, don't be like that!
Don't be like that, 'Toy!
Of course, I'm happy.
We've wanted this for her
for so long, right?
[pensive music playing]
[sighs] But of course, I need…
I want to make sure
she goes to the right person.
[melancholic music playing]
Oh?
Why do you have doubts about the mother?
[Atoy] A little.
'Son…
I need you to do something.
Hmm?
Go to our contact clinic at the corner.
Give them this.
[suspicious music playing]
This is Olga's specimen sample.
And this, Ibyang's swab specimen.
Request a maternity match test.
Tell them it's rush.
If they agree,
we'll get the result tomorrow.
Okay. Of course, sure.
I got you.
But… Rush? Does that mean right away?
Maybe I can go home first, take a bath?
- 'Son, this is important.
- [in English] Rush, rush.
[music swells]
Okay, okay, okay, okay. All right.
[suspicious music playing]
Rush, you said.
- Who's that?
- Ah--
[clears throat] Hi!
About-- Ah, ah, ah-- Sir Atoy!
Oh?
Uh, I left my shades.
I just came back for them.
Where-- Where could they be?
- Shades? Your shades?
- Yes.
Yes!
Oh?
But you weren't wearing shades earlier.
Excuse me. I'm Faye.
No, I was wearing them earlier.
- No. Are you sure?
- Huh? I wasn't?
Oh, yes! I wasn't, I wasn't.
Okay, I'll leave now.
- Okay.
- I'll leave now. About--
- I'll go home now.
- Okay.
[tense music playing]
‪So, bro…
- Okay.
- Yes, okay.
- You handle it.
- Yes.
- What's that?
- For taxi, food,
payment for the test. It's expensive.
- You'll cash it?
- Oh.
I'll transfer the rest for the test.
- Yes, for the test.
- For the test. You take care of it.
- For snacks, and for--
- Psst.
- [in English] Covert-- Covert ops. Okay?
- [in English] Okay.
- [in English] Okay?
- [in English] Okay. Okay, okay. Yes, sir.
- 'Son.
- [in English] Okay.
[Emerson] I'll handle it.
I'll handle it, 'Toy.
- [in English] Thank you!
- [Emerson] All right!
[sighs]
[music fades]
When we used to live in the bus,
unstable, and…
- [thunder rumbling]
- unsafe with tetanus…
- [Ame] One turn, and it's
already the kitchen.
[chuckling softly]
Then we turn around,
it's our bed.
Then we sleep facing each other.
But no moving!
- I almost fell, right?
- Mm-hmm.
But you pulled me back.
[chuckles]
Sis Ame.
Thank you for taking care of me.
- [sentimental music playing]
- [dramatic sting]
[Ibyang] Thank you for loving me.
You became my family.
You were also my only family.
I'm so lucky,
I was given the chance
to be with such a kind and loving child.
[sentimental music playing]
Sis Ame.
Can't you come with me?
[sniffles]
No.
It's your time now to be with your mama.
Even if we don't sleep
side by side anymore,
even if we don't share the same house,
I'll still be your Sister Ame.
And I can still visit you there.
Promise, okay?
Yes, Ibyang. Promise.
[in English] Promise. [inhales] Promise.
Can I hug you a little longer?
I haven't bathed yet.
That's okay.
[sobs] I want to keep your scent with me.
And here, on our bed.
So, when you're with your mama,
I won't feel too sad.
Hmm?
[pensive music playing]
Sis Ame.
[sentimental music playing]
I'll miss you.
What about me?
But it's okay because…
I know…
that you'll be happier there.
That your identity will be complete.
[music fades]
Sister Ame won't be there.
[sobs]
Be good there, okay.
[sentimental music playing]
Hey! What?
Hasn't Martina's man arrived yet?
Emerson might leave.
They said he's on his way.
It's taking too long.
He should've been here earlier.
- [knocks]
- [gasps]
- Are you Olga?
Yes, that's me.
We've been waiting for you, sir.
Madam Martina sent this.
Here's what you need.
[suspicious music playing]
Perfect! Wait! Don't leave yet.
I still need you.
Let me borrow some clothes, sis.
Oh, here.
Perfect, I brought a costume for you.
Sir, listen carefully.
This role is crucial.
You need to understand it well.
Here's the plan.
We'll go inside that tailoring shop.
Then we'll pretend to be a wealthy couple.
You'll act like you're buying,
and when he measures you,
you need to distract him.
- Okay? Clear?
- Clear, madam.
[man] Excuse me.
I'd like to have a suit tailored.
[sneaky music playing]
Ah, sorry.
Maybe… you can come back later,
because I have an errand.
I'm closing the shop now.
Oh, no.
So, you refuse clients?
[in English] That's bad for business.
[sighs] Too bad.
We were going to order an entire entourage
for my child's wedding.
Well, if you don't want to,
then forget it. Let's go, honey.
Ah, ah-- No, no. Wait, wait.
You didn't say so.
Um, this will be quick.
Let me measure your husband first.
I'll start with him. Sir, come here.
- We're in a hurry too--
- You didn't say so.
Here, sir. Ah, let's remove that.
[Emerson] Ah, there.
[in English] Neck, that.
[in English] Armhole.
Good thing you thought
of having your suit made here
and not at Sir Delfin's.
Yes, because…
I didn't like the vibes there.
- [Emerson] Oh, really?
- [Olga] Mmm-hmm.
Ah, good thing you came here.
[giggles]
- Will this take long?
- [in English] Okay.
- Okay. All right.
- [Olga] Done?
Yes, um…
Just leave your contact number
so I can call you with the details.
Oh, no. We'll just come back.
- Okay, okay.
- [Olga] All right, all right.
- [in English] Thank you.
- [Emerson, in English] Okay.
- Yes, yes.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
- [in English] Let's go, hon.
[tense music playing]
Ah, jackpot.
[in English] Okay, okay.
So, that's it.
Miss Cita said
Ibyang's RL mother arrived!
RL, RL.
What's RL?
RL, "real life"! In real life!
There, see! Miss Siony is very good!
- Always updated with…
- The latest terms.
- [man] Yes.
- That's why Miss Siony always looks good.
- Of course, That's Miss Siony.
- [man] Miss Siony.
[sneaky music playing]
[chuckling]
- Hey, come eat!
- Oh, Karla.
Come, sit here first.
Have you heard the news?
Yes. Sis Ame texted me.
It's good that Ibyang
is with her real mother.
Ah!
What if Ibyang leaves?
What about Brother Atoy?
[T-Bak] Then he'll go solo in life!
No. Sis Ame is still there,
and Miss Cita too.
Oh, but Cita's gone! She resigned.
Why isn't your mom there, Karla?
[suspicious music playing]
Do she and Atoy have a problem, child?
Um, well-- [clears throat]
No, it's…
Miss Cita, she just went on vacation.
Mm-hmm. Of course,
she has to relax when there's time.
Yes.
You know, Atoy should take a vacation too.
Well, if you get the chance,
any of you, check on Atoy.
Even if we know him as strong,
brave, steadfast,
he also feels pain from losing Ibyang.
As far as I know,
he treated the child like his own.
That's true, Father.
[melancholic music playing]
[pensive music playing]
[phone ringing]
Oh, 'Tols?
[Emerson on the phone]
'Toy, I just want to know…
has the DNA test result
been emailed to you?
They're sending it today.
Yes, it arrived.
Positive, Emerson.
She really is the mother.
[pensive music playing]
[Emerson on the phone] Oh, there you go.
You said you'd be happy, right?
Okay then. We'll talk later.
[music fades]
[clears throat]
[footsteps approaching]
[knocks]
Hello!
Oh. Hello, Atoy! I'm here to fetch Ibyang.
Yes.
Uh, she's just…
Where's Olga? Why--
- Uh…
- [Atoy] Isn't she fetching her?
Olga is at home, cleaning.
Preparing for Ibyang's arrival.
Will Ibyang take long?
Ah, no. She's ready too.
- I'll just call her.
- Okay.
[melodramatic music playing]
[electronic blipping]
- [tense music playing]
- [electronic blipping]
It's really hard to fight loneliness,
isn't it?
[Atoy] Think about it, just recently,
Ibyang came into my life.
Then, my family.
And now they're all gone.
They came quickly, but…
were taken from me just as fast.
UP NEXT
[in English] I was ordered
by Colonel Mercado to meet you
and deliver his directives.
[goon actor 1] The job could've been easy,
but they're making it hard.
Exactly. Olga is such a headache.
[goon actor 1] We'll kill her anyway.
[gasps]
[music swells]
Mama!
[groans]
[objects clanging and clattering]
[in English] Hey! Cut!
[director] What's happening here?
[music swells]
[gunshots]
[security officer, in English]
We used AI to see what he might look like.
I want you to find out
everything about this man.
[grunting and groaning]
[gunshots]
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias